<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Experiences on Steven Zhu</title>
    <link>http://www.stevenzhujr.com/experiences/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Experiences on Steven Zhu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="http://www.stevenzhujr.com/experiences/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Optical Communications and Atomic Quantum Photonic Integration Group - 5/2024 to Present</title>
      <link>http://www.stevenzhujr.com/experiences/ocpi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.stevenzhujr.com/experiences/ocpi/</guid>
      <description>I am currently a researcher in Professor Blumenthal&amp;rsquo;s Optical Communications and Atomic Quantum Photonic Integration Group at the University of California, Santa Barbara.
Some of the things I did in this lab include:
Utilizing gdsfactory, a Python library, to design photonic chips Analyzing data to evaluate the performances of optical devices Planning and coordinating testing efforts with research group members Gauging the quality factor of optical frequency combs This research experience has significantly enhanced my technical skills in photonics and data analysis, deepened my understanding of optical communications, and honed my ability to work collaboratively in a research team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trina Solar - 5/2022 to 9/2022</title>
      <link>http://www.stevenzhujr.com/experiences/trina/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.stevenzhujr.com/experiences/trina/</guid>
      <description>I was a sales and operations (SOP) intern at Trina during the summer of 2022, from May until September.
At this internship, my main responsibilities included:
Preparing and presenting weekly operational reports regarding relevant statistics Data entry and creation of invoices Heading and developing a key performance index (KPI) project Automated Slides
This is a personal project started to automate the weekly updating operational report. Learn more about it here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University of California, Facility Services Manager - 9/2024 to Present</title>
      <link>http://www.stevenzhujr.com/experiences/fsm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.stevenzhujr.com/experiences/fsm/</guid>
      <description>I am currently a Facility Services Manager (FSM) at the University of California - Santa Barbara.
In this job, my main responsibilities included:
Operating audio and video equipment for school events and conferences Providing technical support to event attendees Setting up rooms according to event specifications This job has taught me valuable skills in technical support and event management, as well as the ability to articulate comprehensively and solve problems under pressure.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
