<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Steven Zhu</title>
    <link>http://www.stevenzhujr.com/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Steven Zhu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="http://www.stevenzhujr.com/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Conrad&#39;s Game of Life</title>
      <link>http://www.stevenzhujr.com/projects/conrad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.stevenzhujr.com/projects/conrad/</guid>
      <description>This is my project implementing Conrad&amp;rsquo;s game of life. This project uses Java and works closely with the Java AWT library.
Github Link to heading https://github.com/stevenzhujr/Conrad/tree/main
Abstract Link to heading This personal project consists of code that simulates Conrad&amp;rsquo;s Game of Life using Java. The main goal of this project is to demonstrate my familiarity with Java as well as learn more about working with graphics.
Rules Link to heading The universe of the Game of Life is an infinite two-dimensional orthogonal grid of square cells, each of which is in one of two possible states, alive or dead, or &amp;ldquo;populated&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;unpopulated&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FlipFlop Clock</title>
      <link>http://www.stevenzhujr.com/projects/clock/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.stevenzhujr.com/projects/clock/</guid>
      <description>This is my project creating a clock. The clock is implemented using a PCB. (Printed Circuit Board) This project uses Kicad and demonstrates understanding of flipflops, counters, and the circuitry design process.
Abstract Link to heading This is a guided project done in collaboration with IEEE. The main goal of this project is to reinforce my understanding of flipflops and counters.
Design Link to heading Goal The goal of the ornament is to make a functional 24 hour clock.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PCB Ornament</title>
      <link>http://www.stevenzhujr.com/projects/pcb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.stevenzhujr.com/projects/pcb/</guid>
      <description>This is my project creating a printed circuit board (PCB) ornament. This project uses Kicad and demonstrates understanding of the circuitry design process.
Abstract Link to heading This is a guided project done in collaboration with IEEE. The main goal of this project is to familiarize myself with PCB and hardware design.
Process Link to heading The process for designing basic circuitry requires three major steps:
Understanding the digital logic for a phenomenon</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pingpong Rapid Defence Turret Repeater(PRDTR)</title>
      <link>http://www.stevenzhujr.com/projects/pingpong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.stevenzhujr.com/projects/pingpong/</guid>
      <description>The Pingpong Rapid Defence Turret Repeater(PRDTR), or the Pingpong Ball Launcher project, was the final assignment of my ECE 5 course. I produced the launcher with two classmates, Vihan Jayaraman and Jerry Wang.
Abstract Link to heading The main goal of our project was to construct a device that shoots projectiles with multiple degrees of freedom. We mounted a ping-pong ball launcher on a tiltable mount, giving it 360 degrees of coverage in aim.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Slides Automation Project</title>
      <link>http://www.stevenzhujr.com/projects/slides/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.stevenzhujr.com/projects/slides/</guid>
      <description>The Weekly Slides Automation Project was made during my internship at Trina.
Github Link to heading https://github.com/stevenzhujr/Slides
Abstract Link to heading The main goal of this project was to write a program that would update slides automatically every week. I used Python and its various libraries to fetch the needed elements from the web, process them, and then update the slides.
The code is composed of the following parts: Link to heading Webfetch: Using Selenium, I could open browsers remotely.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
