<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Steven Zhu</title>
    <link>http://www.stevenzhujr.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Steven Zhu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="http://www.stevenzhujr.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>http://www.stevenzhujr.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.stevenzhujr.com/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a Sophomore studying computer engineering at University of California, Santa Barbara.
During the last summer of highschool, I interned at a company named Trina Solar. This opportunity was my introduction to work culture. My task included data entry and to lead presentations within the company. Currently, I am working part time at UCSB as a Facility Services Operator. I was trained in elementary operations with audio and video equipment, as well as furthered my skill in interpersonal communication and scheduling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://www.stevenzhujr.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.stevenzhujr.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>Email: stevenzhu@ucsb.edu
Phone number: 668-241-9173</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ping pong</title>
      <link>http://www.stevenzhujr.com/projects/pingpong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.stevenzhujr.com/projects/pingpong/</guid>
      <description>The Ping pong Rapid Defence Turret Repeater(PRDTR), is a ping pong ball launcher that was the subject of my ECE 5 course. Me and two other classmates, Vihan Jayaraman, and Jerry Wang, created this as our final project.
Abstract Link to heading The main goal of our project was to construct a device that would be able to shoot projectiles with multiple degrees of freedom. We mounted a ping-pong ball launcher on a tiltable mount, giving it 360 degrees of coverage as well as the ability to change the angle of aim.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>http://www.stevenzhujr.com/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.stevenzhujr.com/projects/</guid>
      <description>Ping pong ball launcher
Weekly updating slides</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides</title>
      <link>http://www.stevenzhujr.com/projects/slides/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.stevenzhujr.com/projects/slides/</guid>
      <description>This weekly slides updating program was made by me during my internship at Trina. It was mainly used weekly during my internship.
Github Link to heading https://github.com/stevenzhujr/Slides
Abstract Link to heading The main goal of this project was to write a program that would update slides weekly. I used python and its various libaries to fetch the needed elements from the web, treat them, and then update the slides.
Parts Link to heading Webfetch: Using Selenium, I could open browsers remotely.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
